Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Follow heavenly principles,
اتبع المبادئ السماوية،
suppress human desires.
قمع الرغبات الإنسانية.
Maintain moderation,
الحفاظ على الاعتدال،
adapt to the ways of the world.
التكيف مع طرق العالم.
The Book of Changes
كتاب التغيرات
is recited to illuminate reason.
يُتلى لتوضيح العقل.
Why is it so noisy today?
لماذا كل هذا الضجيج اليوم؟
I really can't stay here long.
لا أستطيع البقاء هنا لفترة طويلة حقًا.
Young Master Xie
السيد الشاب شيه
Why are you still here?
لماذا مازلت هنا؟
Lady Rong Heng
السيدة رونغ هينغ
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
The Imperial Kitchen prepared lots of fresh ingredients.
قام المطبخ الإمبراطوري بإعداد الكثير من المكونات الطازجة.
All the palace officials are busy buying supplies.
جميع مسؤولي القصر مشغولون بشراء الإمدادات.
Go take a look quickly.
اذهب وألقي نظرة بسرعة.
Sister Rong Heng
الأخت رونغ هينغ
The Princess is calling you.
الأميرة تناديك.
I'll be right there.
سأكون هناك حالا.
Young Master Xie
السيد الشاب شيه
Go on, hurry.
إذهب، بسرعة.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Since the assessment is related to this,
وبما أن التقييم مرتبط بهذا،
I'll see what tricks I can come up with.
سأرى ما هي الحيل التي يمكنني التوصل إليها.
Du Momo
يو مومو
These people have no sense at all.
هؤلاء الناس ليس لديهم أي إحساس على الإطلاق.
I've been standing here for so long.
لقد وقفت هنا لفترة طويلة.
Let me tell you some good news.
دعني أخبرك ببعض الأخبار الجيدة.
Yesterday, the Imperial Kitchen
أمس، المطبخ الإمبراطوري
got a batch of fresh ingredients.
حصلت على دفعة من المكونات الطازجة.
I thought you needed to prepare a culinary offering.
اعتقدت أنك بحاجة إلى إعداد عرض طهي.
So,
لذا،
I had them delivered here first.
لقد قمت بتسليمهم هنا أولاً.
So you could pick first.
لذا يمكنك الاختيار أولاً.
Thank you, Du Momo.
شكرا لك، دو مومو.
Take a look.
خذ نظرة.
Aren't these just ordinary ginseng and seafood?
أليست هذه مجرد الجينسنغ والمأكولات البحرية العادية؟
And these river clams.
وهذه المحار النهري.
The Princess is tired of eating them.
لقد سئمت الأميرة من أكلهم.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Momo
يكتب
Young Master Xie
السيد الشاب شيه
What are we doing here?
ماذا نفعل هنا؟
The palace holds a night banquet every festival.
يقيم القصر مأدبة ليلية في كل مهرجان.
We all have to present a culinary offering.
يتوجب علينا جميعًا تقديم عرض طهي.
A culinary offering?
عرض الطهي؟
Yes.
نعم.
Is this my assessment?
هل هذا تقييمي؟
Yes, Young Master Xie.
نعم، السيد الشاب شيه.
You can't be unaware, right?
لا يمكنك أن تكون غافلاً، أليس كذلك؟
You should look and pick too.
ينبغي عليك أن تنظر وتختار أيضاً.
We'll need them later.
سوف نحتاجهم لاحقا.
They were gathered by people over there.
لقد تم تجميعهم من قبل الناس هناك.
They rushed here at top speed.
لقد وصلوا إلى هنا بأقصى سرعة.
It takes two months to reach Jin City.
يستغرق الوصول إلى مدينة جين شهرين.
The Imperial Kitchen only has these three.
المطبخ الإمبراطوري يحتوي فقط على هذه الثلاثة.
Since that's the case,
وبما أن هذه هي الحالة،
I'll take the ten taels of silver.
سوف آخذ العشرة تايل من الفضة.
I want it.
أريدها.
Here it is.
ها هو.
Careless, careless.
مهمل، مهمل.
I actually forgot.
لقد نسيت فعلا.
It's Young Master Xie's first time at the banquet.
إنها المرة الأولى التي يحضر فيها السيد الشاب شيه إلى المأدبة.
Here.
هنا.
This is the banquet procedure and notes.
هذه هي إجراءات الحفل والملاحظات.
Hope it helps Young Master Xie pass the assessment.
آمل أن يساعد ذلك الشاب السيد شيه في اجتياز التقييم.
And earn the City Lord's reward.
واحصل على مكافأة سيد المدينة.
Sea cucumber.
خيار البحر.
Cordyceps.
كورديسيبس.
Snow lotus from Tianshan.
لوتس الثلج من تيانشان.
Such extravagance and waste.
مثل هذا الإسراف والتبذير.
I don't need it.
لا أحتاجه.
Five taels of gold.
خمسة تايل من الذهب.
Ten taels of gold.
عشرة تايل من الذهب.
Twenty taels.
عشرون تايل.
Everyone,
الجميع،
do you know
هل تعلم؟
in this world,
في هذا العالم،
many people are still starving.
لا زال الكثير من الناس يعانون من الجوع.
Such fine ingredients
مثل هذه المكونات الجميلة
might be food they've never tasted in their lives.
قد يكون الطعام الذي لم يتذوقوه في حياتهم أبدًا.
Just for one dish,
فقط لطبق واحد،
you are so picky,
أنت انتقائي للغاية
so extravagant and wasteful.
مُبذّر ومُبذّر للغاية.
Don't you feel ashamed?
ألا تشعر بالخجل؟
Princess
أميرة
Didn't I tell you to secretly help Xiao Yuanyuan?
ألم أخبرك بمساعدة شياو يوان يوان سراً؟
Why did you come back?
لماذا عدت؟
Princess
أميرة
I'm here for that very reason.
أنا هنا لهذا السبب بالذات.
That's my Xiao Yuanyuan.
هذا هو شياو يوان يوان الخاص بي.
Well done.
أحسنت.
This assessment still needs to be
لا يزال هذا التقييم بحاجة إلى أن يتم
discussed with the Second Princess.
ناقشت مع الأميرة الثانية.
Xie Yuan is so perfunctory about this banquet.
كان شي يوان سطحيًا جدًا بشأن هذه المأدبة.
He's really not as good as Mo Yu and Zhao Xiang.
إنه ليس جيدًا حقًا مثل مو يو وتشاو شيانغ.
Why are you still so happy?
لماذا لا تزال سعيدا جدا؟
What do you know?
ماذا تعرف؟
All the men in this city
كل الرجال في هذه المدينة
just flatter this Princess.
فقط أثني على هذه الأميرة.
It's so boring.
إنه أمر ممل للغاية.
But Xiao Yuanyuan is different.
لكن شياو يوان يوان مختلف.
Young Master Xie
السيد الشاب شيه
A ghost!
شبح!
It's me.
هذا أنا.
Ruo Lin!
رو لين!
Ruo Lin.
رو لين.
It's me.
هذا أنا.
Ruo Lin has finally waited for you.
لقد انتظرتك رو لين أخيرًا.
You've been chopping wood here all this time?
لقد كنت تقطع الخشب هنا كل هذا الوقت؟
Yes.
نعم.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Ruo Lin has sacrificed so much for you.
لقد ضحى رو لين بالكثير من أجلك.
A huge sacrifice.
تضحية كبيرة.
You lost that thing.
لقد فقدت هذا الشيء.
Which one?
أيها؟
That one.
هذا.
Just...
فقط...
A man's most precious thing.
أغلى ما يملكه الرجل.
It's still here.
إنه لا يزال هنا.
It's here.
إنه هنا.
But it almost...
ولكن تقريبا...
Forget it, never mind.
انسى الأمر، لا يهم.
Anyway, Ruo Lin only needs to chop wood now.
على أية حال، رو لين يحتاج فقط إلى تقطيع الخشب الآن.
Nothing else matters.
لا شىئ اخر يهم.
As long as it's still here.
طالما أنها لا تزال هنا.
As long as it's here, that's enough.
ما دام الأمر هنا، فهذا يكفي.
Do you want to check?
هل تريد التحقق؟
No need, no need.
لا حاجة، لا حاجة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Want to eat?
هل تريد أن تأكل؟
What?
ماذا؟
Steamed bun.
مطهو على البخار جيدًا.
You eat this every day?
هل تأكل هذا كل يوم؟
Yes.
نعم.
It's delicious.
إنه لذيذ.
You've really had it tough.
لقد كان الأمر صعبًا حقًا.
Go ahead and eat.
تفضل وتناول الطعام.
I eat pretty well in the palace.
أنا آكل جيداً في القصر.
Then I'll eat.
ثم سأكل
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
When I heard the Princess took in a handsome man,
عندما سمعت أن الأميرة أخذت رجلاً وسيمًا،
and he was from Yue,
وكان من يوي،
I thought about it.
لقد فكرت في هذا الأمر.
It had to be you, Young Master Xie.
لقد كان لا بد أن تكون أنت، السيد الشاب شيه.
So I tried my luck entering the palace.
لذلك حاولت حظي بالدخول إلى القصر.
Who knew I'd end up in the wood shed.
من كان يعلم أنني سأنتهي في سقيفة الحطب.
I wanted to find you.
لقد أردت أن أجدك.
But the palace is so huge.
لكن القصر ضخم جدًا.
I also...
أنا أيضاً...
Ruo Lin...
رو لين ...
You've really suffered.
لقد عانيت حقا.
When we get out,
عندما نخرج،
I'll find you a good wife.
سأجد لك زوجة صالحة.
No need.
لا حاجة.
Ruo Lin just needs to find you.
روو لين تحتاج فقط إلى العثور عليك.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
Ruo Lin.
رو لين.
You've been here so long,
لقد كنت هنا لفترة طويلة،
Have you found a way out?
هل وجدت طريقا للخروج؟
Ruo Lin was busy looking for you.
كان رو لين مشغولاً بالبحث عنك.
Didn't think about escaping.
لم أفكر في الهروب.
But I know,
ولكنني أعلم
The one who brought me in said,
الذي أدخلني قال:
Once you enter the palace,
بمجرد دخولك القصر،
you're a servant for life.
أنت خادم مدى الحياة.
That's it.
هذا كل شيء.
Looks like I need my own plan.
يبدو أنني بحاجة إلى خطتي الخاصة.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
You have a way out?
هل لديك طريقة للخروج؟
Of course I do.
بالطبع أفعل.
Here,
هنا،
the Hot Spring Palace sends people out daily to buy supplies.
يرسل قصر الينابيع الساخنة الناس يوميًا لشراء الإمدادات.
We sneak in with them.
نحن نتسلل معهم.
Wear their clothes.
ارتدوا ملابسهم.
Then we can get out.
ثم يمكننا الخروج.
Yes, Young Master Xie.
نعم، السيد الشاب شيه.
We leave tonight.
سنغادر الليلة.
That was the plan.
هذه كانت الخطة.
But they found out I knew.
لكنهم اكتشفوا أنني أعرف.
So they changed the rules.
لذلك قاموا بتغيير القواعد.
We can't get out now.
لا يمكننا الخروج الآن.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
So your plan was for nothing.
لذلك خطتك كانت بلا فائدة.
Just like you.
مثلك تماما.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Each day here means chopping one hundred logs.
كل يوم هنا يعني تقطيع مائة جذع شجرة.
Two days, two hundred logs.
يومان ومائتي سجل.
Three days, three hundred logs.
ثلاثة أيام، ثلاثمائة سجل.
I know you're suffering.
أعلم أنك تعاني.
Give me some time.
أعطني بعض الوقت.
Once I find a way out,
بمجرد أن أجد طريقا للخروج،
I'll get us both out.
سأخرجنا معًا.
Can you wait for me?
هل يمكنك الانتظار بالنسبة لي؟
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Okay.
تمام.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
This palace is so big.
هذا القصر كبير جداً.
Too many people and eyes here.
هناك الكثير من الناس والعيون هنا.
I have things to do.
لدي أشياء للقيام بها.
I have to go.
يجب على  أن أذهب.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
I'll see you off.
سأراك.
Know yourself and your enemy,
اعرف نفسك واعرف عدوك
and you will never be defeated.
ولن تهزم أبدًا.
If you know only yourself,
إذا كنت تعرف نفسك فقط،
you win some, lose some.
تربح بعضًا، وتخسر ​​بعضًا.
Princess.
أميرة.
Young Master Xie is here.
السيد الشاب شيه هنا.
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Greetings, Second Princess.
تحياتي، الأميرة الثانية.
No need for formalities.
لا حاجة إلى أي إجراءات شكلية.
Princess.
أميرة.
Are you really pawning all these jewels to help the people?
هل حقا تقومون برهن كل هذه الجواهر لمساعدة الناس؟
How have I taught you?
كيف علمتك؟
These are just worldly possessions.
هذه مجرد ممتلكات دنيوية.
If they can help the people,
إذا كان بإمكانهم مساعدة الناس،
then their existence is worthwhile.
ثم إن وجودهم يستحق العناء.
Young Master Xie, you came today
السيد الشاب شيه، لقد أتيت اليوم
to ask a favor.
لطلب معروف.
The palace banquet is approaching.
مأدبة القصر تقترب.
I wish to fail the assessment on purpose.
أتمنى أن أفشل في التقييم عمداً.
However,
لكن،
the culinary offering here is always extravagant.
العروض المطبخية هنا دائما باهظة الثمن.
Just do the opposite, and you'll fail.
فقط افعل العكس، وسوف تفشل.
Xiao Cui.
شياو كوي.
Why is it crab pastry again?
لماذا هي فطيرة السلطعون مرة أخرى؟
Where's my favorite radish cake?
أين كعكة الفجل المفضلة لدي؟
Forgive me, Princess.
سامحيني يا أميرتي.
The Imperial Kitchen said radish is cheap.
قال المطبخ الإمبراطوري أن الفجل رخيص الثمن.
It's not worthy of your status.
إنه لا يليق بمكانتك.
So they stopped making it.
لذلك توقفوا عن صنعه.
Who says ingredients have ranks and worth?
من قال أن المكونات لها رتب وقيمة؟
Young Master Xie.
السيد الشاب شيه.
Ruo Lin.
رو لين.
Everything you asked for is here.
كل ما طلبته موجود هنا.
But what do you need these for?
ولكن لماذا تحتاج إلى هذه الأشياء؟
You'll know soon enough.
سوف تعرف قريبا بما فيه الكفاية.
Go ahead.
تفضل.
Be careful.
احرص.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Xiao Tao
شياو تاو
You said Young Master Xie locked himself in his room, acting all mysterious.
قلت أن السيد الشاب شيه حبس نفسه في غرفته، وكان يتصرف بطريقة غامضة.
What is he up to in there?
ماذا يفعل هناك؟
Can he pass the assessment?
هل يستطيع اجتياز التقييم؟
I think he can.
أعتقد أنه يستطيع ذلك.
The banquet is coming soon.
المأدبة قادمة قريبا.
Let's see what surprises Young Master Xie will bring.
دعونا نرى ما هي المفاجآت التي سيجلبها السيد الشاب شيه.
No.
لا.
I can't wait any longer.
لا أستطيع الانتظار لفترة أطول.
Go gather everyone.
اذهبوا وجمعوا الجميع.
I want to taste the dishes myself.
أريد أن أتذوق الأطباق بنفسي.
If Xiao Yuanyuan doesn't prepare well,
إذا لم يستعد شياو يوان يوان جيدًا،
the Queen Mother will be furious.
ستكون الملكة الأم غاضبة.
Yes.
نعم.
Princess.
أميرة.